The credit for today's video goes to the comment of this gentleman.
Thank you for your comment sir.  If you all want to know about the Poorna Suraksha Kavach Plan of Aditya Birla
Sun Life Insurance Company Limited
then
check the description of the video.  You will get the link to the video.
Now as you know
that every video on the channel
comes according to your questions, suggestions and comments.
Including Post Office and Government
Saving Scheme.  So on this note, please
like the video, share it and
subscribe to the channel and turn on all the notification bells
because
only when you turn on the notification bells will you be able to get the latest videos
and updates.  Along with this, you
must tell us in the comment section
which plan or topic you want the next video to be
related to.  Hello everyone,
you all are very welcome.  You're watching
You the Real.  I am your
personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma.  In today's
video we will understand the information related to Param Suraksha Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited.
This
plan is a unit linked non-participating
individual life insurance savings plan.
Simply put,
this is a market-related plan.  The premium that you
pay to the insurance company will be
invested in the market by the company with the help of the fund investment option chosen by you and when the company
invests your money in the market, the
risk on it will be yours.  This means that
there is market related risk involved which
you have to bear.  If you complete the policy term by
paying premiums continuously,
then at the end of maturity you are
given the fund value as a maturity benefit.  The
policy gets closed which you
can also take in installments.  Now if the
plan is in the life insurance category, then
your life insurance is also there during the policy term.   This
means that if something happens to you, your nominee is
given a guaranteed benefit.  Which
you decide at the time of taking the plan.
Let us now know about the eligibility criteria of Param Suraksha Plan of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company.  The
age limit for taking the Param Suraksha Plan is from 18 years to 50
years and
you will be able to remain under the cover of the plan only till the maximum age of 75 years.   When it comes to the
policy term, you can take a policy term of 15 years, 20
years, 25 years, 26 years, 27 years, 28, 29 years and even up to
30 years.  If we
talk about the
premium payment term, then
you get the option of premium payment term ranging from 6 years to 12 years
i.e. 6 years, 8 years, 10 years and 12 years.  The
minimum premium
limit for this plan has been kept at ₹1 lakh.
And the minimum sum assured that
you can take is up to seven times the annual premium.
Minimum.  There
is more maximum which we will tell you at the end through examples.
Let us now learn about the
investment options or
portfolio strategy options of the Param Suraksha Plan.
So the first option is the systematic
transfer option.  Now we are talking about systematic transfer,
so here
you will get this option only when you pay the premium in annual mode.  The
premium paid by you will be
directly transferred by the insurance company to the Liquid Plus Fund
i.e. invested.
Then after that, what about the funds of your choice
i.e. Liquid Plus Fund?   It's
fixed.  Apart from that, if
you choose any fund from the other fund options,
units will be transferred to it on a monthly basis.
What will be the other fund options?  Income
Advantage Nature Maximizer Super 20 Cap
Nifty Index Fund Multiplier Volume
& Momentum Fund along with Creator Fund
MAC Fund ESG Fund and Small Cap Fund
Nifty Alpha 50 Index Fund have also been
included.  This means that
you will choose the fund option and also decide the allocation of premium.
The allocation you decide is
managed by the company through the policy term under the systematic transfer.
Right?  But units from the liquid fund will be automatically
transferred to your chosen fund every month.
The second is the Return
Optimizer.  Two funds have been fixed in this.  The
first is equity based fund which
is maximizer fund.  That means you
paid the premium and the insurance company
invested it in the maximizer fund.
Now as soon as the gain in Maximizer Fund
is 10%, that is, the amount you have
invested after the premium
allocation chart, when it increases by 10%, at
least or even if it increases more than that, then
here the pre-determined upside movement
rate is given of 10%, as soon as the plan
increases by 10%, the company will transfer it to Income Advantage Fund, that is, the
gain will be
transferred to Debt Fund which is
Income Advantage Fund.  Now the advantage of this is that
like in the equity market,
because there is risk, if there is a sharper downfall in equity, then
your return is saved because
in Income Advantage, debt fund does not have that much risk.
Right?  The third option here is the
smart investment option.  Now
when you choose the Smart Investment option,
you get three options of risk profile here.
Aggressive Option, Moderate Option
and Conservative Option.  Aggressive means
higher equity exposure.  Moderate is
mixed and conservative is a
combination of equity and debt.
In this option also you get two funds which are
inbuilt and fixed.
Maximizer and Income Advantage.  Now the
outstanding term to maturity written here
means the number of years
left for maturity.  Suppose you have taken the aggressive option
and according to your policy term, you have
21 years or more
left for maturity.  So in such a situation, whatever
is your premium, whatever will be the investment, whatever will be the fund,
90% of it will remain in the Maximizer Fund.
And 10% will go into Income Advantage Fund
because it is an aggressive option and there is a
lot of time for maturity.  Therefore,
if your policy term has
20 to 16 years left for maturity, then
80% will go into equity
in Maximizer Fund and 20% in Income Advantage Fund.  At
the same time, if you are left with 8 to 15 years to
reach maturity or if you are left with 15 to 8
years, then 65% of
your investment will be in the Maximizer Fund.  The
Queries are here to stay.  The remaining
35% is invested in Income Advantage Fund.  When there are
4 to 7 years left for maturity or say
7 to 4 years, then it will be 50-50.  The
ratio of equity and debt will be made
equal.  When maturity
comes, in the last 3 years, from zero to
3 years, 20% will remain in equity.  This
means that the remaining
80% of the Maximizer Fund will be transferred to your Day Fund, i.e., Income
Advantage Fund.
When?  Now when you choose the aggressive option.  If you are
taking a ULIP plan and
cannot take market risk then there is
no point in it.  That's why I have
talked about aggressive options here.  And
after taking the plan, you
can also change the risk profile.  You
can move from aggressive to moderate and also to conservative.  The
remaining percentages are at the top of your screen.
Pause and read it.  The next option is the
life cycle investment option.
From the name itself it became clear that
it will depend according to your age.  Only two funds have been
involved here.
Maximizer Fund which is an equity based fund
and the second fund is Income Advantage Fund which is a
debt fund.  Annual mode of premium is available
in this plan.  So as soon as you
pay the annual premium, the premium
allocation charge will be deducted from it.  The donation will then
go into the Premium Maximizer Fund and Equi and Income Advantage Fund.  Suppose
you chose the aggressive option and
your age at the time of purchasing the plan was under 30
years.  So in such a situation, 90% of the
investment will remain within the maximizer fund.
10%
in Income Advantage Fund in Edge Day Fund.  If you have chosen the Moderate option, then
70% of the proceeds will go
to the Maximizer Fund.  The remaining 30% will go
into the Income Advantage Fund.  If the conservative option is
chosen, only 50% will remain
in the maximizer fund.  The remaining 50% in Income Advantage Fund.
When?  When you are under 30.  Or you can say that it is for up
to 30 years at the time of taking the plan.  At the same time,
if your age is in the bracket of 31 years to 40 years,
because this is the age bracket
where most people prefer to take more plans.
Think about investing.  If you take the aggressive option, then
80% will be in Maximizer Fund and the remaining
20% ​​will be in Income Advantage.  If you choose the moderate option,
60% will go to the maximizer fund i.e.
equity and the remaining 40% will
go to debt i.e. income advantage fund.  So in the
same way the edge on S is given here.
You can read by pausing.  Rest
in this option also you can change your risk profile.  You
can move from aggressive to moderate or conservative
during the positive term.  The next option is the
self-manage investment option.
You do everything here.
19 fund options are given within the plan.  You
choose the fund as per your wish.
Decide the premium allocation as per your wish.
And you can also switch from one fund to another whenever you want.
Right?  Along with this, the
plan also offers you riders
on the policy document.  Like, you get
Accidental Benefit Rider plus
Comprehensive Critical Illness Rider
and along with this you
also get Waiver of Premium Rider.
If you have children, are minors and are
taking this plan, then you can take Criticality Rider.  Just
for infatuation, if you will.
Now we will know about the benefits of Param Suraksha Plan of Aditya Birla
Sunlife Insurance Company Limited.   The
first is the return of premium allocation
charge.  You get double the amount of charge deducted.
How to get it?  The
charges deducted from your account in the first year will be reimbursed to you at the end of the 10th year of the policy.
How much will I get?   You will
get double.  I have written Premium Allocation Charge
in short as PAC.  Right?
And the charge that will have to be deducted from you in the second year,
you will get it at the end of the 11th year of the policy.
Premium allocation charge in the plan is deducted only for 4 years.
So in this way you will continue to get
return of premium allocation charge till the end of the 13th year of the policy.  This
means that whatever
premium allocation charge is deducted,
you get it back doubled
under this plan.  Ok?  So the
deduction in the third year will be received at the end of the 12th year.
Right?  Along with this, the
motive charges incurred in the plan are
also returned to you.  In the same way, the
deduction made in the first year
starts getting received from the end of the 11th year, that is, it starts getting received
from the beginning of the 11th year.
As long as your deduction is there, you will keep getting it back accordingly.  You will
get double the amount deducted.  You can switch from one fund to another.  The
minimum
switch should be ₹5,000.
Inside whom?  Self-manage and systematic transfer
options available.  If you wish, you
can also change your investment option
after completion of one year of the policy.  Right?  The next benefit here
is free premium redirection.  You get
12 free premium redirections within 1 year.  If
you feel that the fund in which
you have invested is not performing as expected, then
you can increase or decrease the ratio if you want to invest in another fund.  That is what we
call redirection.  If you feel
that you cannot afford the premium you are paying now,
then
you can reduce the premium after completion of 5 years of the policy.
When you do
this, the sum assured also reduces.
You can take the maturity in installments.
Under the settlement option,
you have to make a request to the company 15 days before the maturity date
and the settlement
period is of 5 years in which you keep getting the
maturity benefit in installments for the next 5 years.
ok sir.  Now here comes the matter
of partial withdrawal.  So this is also an
important benefit.  The
conditions for partial withdrawal are the same that the
first 5 years of the policy must be completed and the
insured must be 18 years of age.   Only then will
partial withdrawal be possible.  The minimum
partial withdrawal limit is ₹5,000.   The
maximum partial withdrawal limit is
25% of your fund value in a one-time request.  Right?  And when you
withdraw, you can get it only
if your fund balance after
withdrawal is equal to your annual premium.
You can withdraw up to 50% of your fund value within a maximum period of 1 year.
But the withdrawal balance, that is, the
fund balance after withdrawal, must be
equal to the annual premium.   The
second option you get is the
systematic withdrawal facility.  Here
also the condition is same that 5 years should be completed
and the age of the insured should be 18 years.   Only
then is systematic withdrawal opted for.
Here the percentage depends on whether you want to
withdraw 5% of your fund value annually
or 10%.
You can avail systematic withdrawal after completion of 5 years of the policy.  As soon as the
policy term is completed, you will get the fund value
as maturity, which you
can take as lump sum or within the settlement period.  That
means, even in installments, the
death benefit in the plan says
that the partial withdrawal will be deducted from the sum assured you have taken.
Which
partial withdrawal?  For example, suppose there is a death, then the
partial withdrawals made in the last two years from the date of death will be deducted
from the sum assured and
105% of the total premium paid will be calculated, from that also the
partial withdrawal of the last two years will be deducted and it will be
compared
with the fund value,
whichever of these three amounts is higher will be the
death benefit which will be paid to the nominee
and after paying the death benefit the
policy gets terminated, so
let us now know about the Param Suraksha Plan charges of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company Limited.
So
here we will know the fund management charges along with the
name and performance of the fund.
For example, the first fund option here is
Liquid Plus which the company has launched at 9.3.  It was
launched in 2012.  The annual fund management charge on this fund will be
1% of your fund value.
You face very little risk in this fund as the
equity exposure is nil and
its average rate of return since the date of inception is
6.46%.  Then there
is Income Advantage Fund which was launched by the company on 22
August 2008.  Its fund
management charge is also only
1% of the average fund value annually.  This is also a fund in the very low
risk category.
Its rate of return from August 2008 till date has been a
little over 8%.  The third fund
option here is Ashor, which was
launched by the company on 12 September 2005.  Its
annual fund management charge is also
1% of your average fund value.
This is also a fund in the very low risk category.
Its average rate of
return from September 2005 till date has been a little over 8%.  The
next option
here is Protector Fund.  The Protector Fund was
launched by the insurance company on 22 March 2001.  In this also, the fund management
charge is 1% of your fund value
annually.  This is a low risk category fund.
Its rate of return has also been a
little more than 8% from March 2001 till
now.  Ok?  And this keeps increasing or decreasing.  It is
not fixed according to time.   The
next fund option is the builder
fund.  This was also launched by the company on 22 March 2001.
Same fund management charge is applicable for the fund
value.  Only 1% interest is charged.
Even in builder funds.  This is also a low risk category fund
and its rate of return from March 2001 till date has been
more than 9%.
This can also be more or less.  The next
fund option is Enhancer Fund.  The
date of inception of the Enhancer Fund remains the same.
22 March 2001.  Now the fund management charge on this fund is
1.25% of your annual average fund value.  The
fund value has also been shortened to F.  It is a
medium risk category fund.
Its rate of return has been a little over 10%.  The
next fund option is the
Creator Fund which was launched by the company on February 23, 2004.  The
fund management charge in this fund will also be
1.25% of the average annual fund value every year.
This fund also falls in the medium risk category and its
average rate of return has been 11.89%.
This may also happen more or less in the future.
Now the next fund option
is Asset Allocation Fund which was
launched by the company on 24 September 2015.  Whom?  To asset
allocation funds.  This fund will also attract a fund management charge of
1.25% of the average annual fund value.  It is a
high
risk category fund.  That means
you get equity exposure here.  Therefore,
its rate of return has been more than 12%.  Let's move on to the
next fund.  The next
fund option is Magnifier.  As you can
see on the screen.  The company launched on 12 August 2004.
Annual fund management charges will be 1.35% of the average fund value for the year.
This fund falls under the high-risk category
and its average rate of return has been
slightly over 13%.  Then the next
fund option is our Maximizer Fund.
See, only if you watch the video in full screen will
you see it clearly.  The company launched on 12 June 2007.  The
fund management charges remain the same.  It is a
high risk category fund with an average fund value of 1.35% per annum.
Its average rate of return has been 11.92%.  On 30
October 2007, the company launched the Multiplier Fund.  It is a
high risk category fund.
Because of this, the equity exposure that
is available here.  If equity exposure
is available, the fund management charge is 1.35%.   of the
annual average fund value.
Its rate of return was more than 14%.   The
next fund option is Super 20 which the
company launched on 6 July 2009.  This
is also a high risk category fund.  So the
fund management charge on this also is
1.35% of the annual average fund value.  And
its rate of return from July 2009 till
now has been 13.27% which
may increase or decrease.  Then there is your pure
equity fund which the company launched on March 9, 2012.
Its fund management charge is also the same.
This fund is in the high risk category with an average fund value of 1.35% per annum.
Its
average rate of return from March 2012 till date has been 18.28%.  The
next fund option is your Value and
Momentum Fund which was launched by the company on March 9, 2012.
Even on this, the fund
management charge that you incur is
only 1.35% of your annual average fund value.
This fund is in the high risk category.
Its average rate of return has been 14.16%.
From March 2012 till now, which may keep increasing or decreasing further.  The
next fund option we
get is Capped Nifty Index Fund
which was launched by the company on 24th September 2015.
Fund management charge will be 1.25% of the average annual fund value.
This fund is in the high risk category.
Its rate of return since 2015 has been a little over 14%.  The
next fund option is our
MAC Fund.  Now this MAC fund is a
high risk category fund, which means it has
more equity exposure.  This also
attracts a fund management charge of 1.35% of the annual average fund value.  The overall
rate of return has been more than 14%.  Now see,
we are not able to get all the information.
Sometimes we do not know the date of inception of this fund,
hence we are not able to tell.
Then comes your ESD fund which is
launched by the company on 21st November 2023.  The fund management
charge is 1.35%
of the average fund value annually. The fund belongs to the high risk
category and has an
average rate of return of over 34%.  Now look, it is a new
fund, that is why it is showing so much, it will
decrease with time and it does decrease.
Mite B may also increase.  The company
launched the Small Cap Fund on November 20, 2023.
You will be charged a fund management charge of 1.35% of the average fund value annually.  It
is a high risk category fund and is showing a rate of return of more than 48%
which can
definitely go wrong in the future.  The company then
launched Nifty Alpha 50 Index Fund on June 18, 2024.  Fund management charges will be
1.35% of the average fund value annually.
This fund is in the high risk category.  Now since it is a new fund, there is
no information available yet about its rate of return.  Then comes your
link discontinue policy fund.  When you
discontinue the policy,
stop paying premiums
prematurely, all your units are transferred to this fund.  There is
no equity exposure in this.  The money can remain yours in government
securities, corporate bonds or money
markets.  Therefore, there is
very low risk and
the guideline on the average rate of return on this is at least 4%.  The
next
charge is the premium allocation charge.
Premium allocation charge of 12% of your annual premium will be applicable in the first year.  That's why
they are returning double the amount because
it is quite high side.  In the second year, a
premium allocation charge of 6% of your annual premium will be charged.  In the
third year, you are charged a
premium allocation charge of 4% of your annual premium
and in the fourth year, you are charged a
premium allocation charge of 3% of your annual premium.  That
means, when you pay the premium, the
company will keep 3% of it in the fourth year.
After that, he will invest further.   I do
n't think so since the fifth year.  Policy
administration charges will be
0.32% of your annual premium every month,
which may increase later.  But the
cap that has been set for this will never exceed ₹500 per
month.  If it happens, you will
definitely be informed first.  Then you
also have to pay a mobility charge which
depends on your age, gender
, lifestyle habits and the amount of sums
you are taking.  Policy
discontinuation charges range from Rs 1000 to Rs 6000.
If you have discontinued the policy within the first 4 years.
This charge is not applicable from the fifth year onwards.
ok sir.  You can watch the video in full screen here
and only then will you understand it if you watch it in high resolution.  The
policy brochure mentions
Mr. Verma, aged 35 years.
He took the Param Suraksha plan from Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited.  He is
paying a premium of ₹1 lakh annually
and has chosen a summed multiplier of
30.  Due to this,
his life cover became 30 times the annual premium i.e. ₹30 lakh.
Want to pay premium for 12 years.  I want to stick to the plan for 30 years
and self-manage
everything.  Hence, he has chosen NFT Alpha 50
Index Fund here and the
policy term is 30 years.  If the rate
of return is 8%, then
they can get a return of around ₹51,72,634.  If it remains at 4%, then
they can get a rate of return of around ₹18,34,424.
Since it is a market based plan, the risk will be
yours.  Right?  This return may be more or
less than this.  There
is no fix.  One thing has been fixed here
for Verma ji that if he dies,
his nominee will get at least ₹30 lakh.
If the remaining fund value
increases, you will get more.  If
partial withdrawal is done then it will be deducted from this.
Thank you very much for patiently watching the video till the end.
Thanks a bundle.  Understand one thing yourself.
Explain to others that insurance is a
protection.  Never take incomplete protection.  If
the information is clear then please
like and share the video.  Stay
connected with us by subscribing to the channel.
Please tell us in the comment section which plan you want the next video to be
about.  All of you please take
care of yourself and before taking a ULIP plan,
read the policy document and
check the fund details because this is the main thing.
Thanks you all.